Md. Tareq Sefati

Full-Stack Java Developer | JavaFX

**** +8801745578700

@ tareq.sefati@gmail.com

Ohaka, Bangladesh

SUMMARY

As a full-stack Java developer, I have expertise on core web and enterprise application development using Java, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Spring Security, React, NextJs and Microservices platform as well as databases and REST web services.

Besides my extensive web development experience, I have dedicated over five years to specializing in JavaFX, focusing on crafting intuitive desktop applications.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Java Developer

Upwork

01/2020 - Present

- JavaFX Desktop application (POS system) development Open Source Project.
- · Java Web application development.

Full Stack Java Developer(Programmer)

Department Of ICT, Government Of Bangladesh.

苗 2019 - Present 👂 Dhaka, Bangladesh

The **Department of Information and Communication Technology** is a government department responsible for information and communication technology projects in Bangladesh

- Developed scalable, responsive applications using modern front-end and back-end technologies.
- Coordinated with product, design, and engineering teams to define technical requirements and prioritize features.

Software Engineer

BJIT Limited

苗 2018 - 2019 👂 Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Developed a high-performance desktop application tool using Core Java, JavaFX, Java Swing, and Amazon SimpleDB with complex UI design.
- Built and maintained RESTful APIs and integrated databases like MongoDB and PostgreSQL to support core application functions.
- Managed version control with Git and configured CI/CD pipelines for efficient deployments.
- Add new features in a Spring Boot web application.

Web Developer

P1, Bashundhara Group

苗 2017 - 2018 👂 Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Collaborated with senior developers to build and improve web applications, contributing to front-end and back-end development using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and frameworks like React and Node.js.
- Assisted in developing RESTful APIs and integrating third-party APIs, improving the functionality and scalability of applications.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Engineering

GPA 3.58 / 4.0

Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology

github.com/TareqSefati

SKILLS

Java	Spring	gBoot	Javal	FX	kafka
Java So	cket	Mong	goDB	MyS	SQL
Docker	Git	_			
React	Node	e.js	Next.js	_	
Tailwind CSS Shaden UI			dcn UI	Da	isy UI
Visual S	Studio (Code	Intelli	J IDE	Α
Eclipse	Net	Beans	Postman		

PROJECTS

Full-stack (MERN) Project

∂ https://github.com/TareqSefati/online-book-shop-ui
E-commerce site to buy or sell books

- Firebase Authentication System
- MongoDB & Redis Integration
- Stripe Payment Method

Desktop Chatting Application

② https://github.com/TareqSefati/ChatApp

JavaFX desktop chat application using java socket programming. This application allows multiple client communication with one another and Chatting group also.

- Implement Java Socket Programming technique
- Implement complex UI using JavaFX

Image To Pdf Converter Software

∂ https://github.com/TareqSefati/ImageToPdf Image To Pdf Converter Software is a simple desktop application developed using JavaFX to generate pdf file from images.

Desktop Image Viewer Application

PassBook

∂ https://github.com/TareqSefati/PassBook
It is a desktop application for password
management to store the corresponding pair of
username and password using JavaFX. Derby
database library is used to store data and JFoenix
JavaFX Material Design Library is used to provide
more beautiful UI.